<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>tobacco_xllp0060</identifier>
  <collection>industry-archives</collection>
  <collection>newsandpublicaffairs</collection>
  <credits>View more information at the &lt;a href="https://www.industrydocuments.ucsf.edu/docs/xllp0060" rel="nofollow"&gt;UCSF Industry Documents Library&lt;/a&gt;</credits>
  <date>1996</date>
  <description>Lorillard Records; video; the witness, the former ceo of lorillard, was deposed by the plaintiffs. he explained that ctr funds research in the tobacco field, whereas the tobacco institute represents the tobacco industrys interests at the legislative level. he described his involvement with the development of the true cigarette. he commented upon the functions and workings of ctr and the advisory board, as well as the level of involvement of any attorneys. he discussed the grant approval process used by the sab and his limited knowledge of the special projects associated with ctr. he maintained that lorillard never advised consumers that it used tobacco leaf that had been contaminated with ddd, which was found to cause tumors on the backs of animals. the witness acknowledged that lorillard has used asbestos in their cigarette filters in the past. he said that he is unaware of any suppression of information within lorillard, and that he would find such behavior offensive. view the transcript of the tape on bates spearsa081396.</description>
  <mediatype>movies</mediatype>
  <subject>tobacco; cigarette; lawsuit ; legal activity; testimony; tobacco industry; laboratory research; nicotine; tobacco industry scientist; cigarette ingredient; nicotine; tar; smoke constituent; low yield cigarette; cancer; asbestos; filter; tobacco related health concerns; industry response; &lt;a href='http://www.archive.org/browse.php?field=subject&amp;mediatype=movies&amp;collection=industry-archives'&gt;Browse by keywords in UCSF Industry Documents&lt;/a&gt;</subject>
  <title>Dr. Spears Deposition [Florida v. American Tobacco Co. ]</title>
  <uploader>sven.maier@ucsf.edu</uploader>
  <publicdate>2021-07-13 21:41:54</publicdate>
  <addeddate>2021-07-13 21:41:54</addeddate>
</metadata>
