<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>tobacco_hla85a00</identifier>
  <mediatype>movies</mediatype>
  <collection>industry-archives</collection>
  <collection>newsandpublicaffairs</collection>
  <date>1997-04-18</date>
  <description>The witness, Chairman, CEO and President of Brown &amp; Williamson Tobacco Company, was deposed by the plaintiffs. He stated that the company's best-selling brand in the U.S. is GPC. He acknowledged that smoking is clearly associated with all the diseases warned about on cigarette packages. He indicated, however, that it has not been scientifically proven that physical smoking or passive smoking causes diseases. His company is not researching whether smoking causes diseases, but it is funding the Council for Tobacco Research to investigate this topic. The witness stated that one purpose of the Frank Statement was to allay the fears that consumers had regarding smoking and diseases. He indicated that it has not been Brown &amp; Williamson's intention to convey to consumers the message that a low-tar cigarette is less hazardous than a high-tar cigarette. He denied that research documents had been destroyed by Brown &amp; Williamson. He admitted that the nicotine in smoke may cause physiological changes in smokers.</description>
  <language>eng</language>
  <scanner>Internet Archive HTML5 Uploader 1.4.1</scanner>
  <subject>tobacco; cigarettes; deposition; advertising; health effects; public awareness; industry activity; addiction; smoking cessation; Passive Smoking; &lt;a href='http://www.archive.org/browse.php?field=subject&amp;mediatype=movies&amp;collection=industry-archives'&gt;Browse by keywords in UCSF industry videos&lt;/a&gt;</subject>
  <title>Deposition of NICHOLAS GEORGE BROOKES, April 18, 1997, BROIN v. PHILIP MORRIS INC.</title>
  <publicdate>2013-10-10 20:35:02</publicdate>
  <uploader>alexia.helenske-oakes@ucsf.edu</uploader>
  <addeddate>2013-10-10 20:35:02</addeddate>
  <year>1997</year>
  <sound>sound</sound>
  <color>color</color>
  <credits>View more information at the &lt;a href="https://www.industrydocuments.ucsf.edu/docs/mrhg0189" rel="nofollow"&gt;UCSF Industry Documents Library&lt;/a&gt;</credits>
  <backup_location>ia905708_7</backup_location>
</metadata>
