<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <identifier>tobacco_pvw10j00</identifier>
  <mediatype>movies</mediatype>
  <collection>industry-archives</collection>
  <collection>newsandpublicaffairs</collection>
  <description>The witness, CEO and President of R.J. Reynolds Tobacco, was deposed by 
the plaintiffs. He began by comparing the marketing position of RJR 
brands to Marlboro, which has been the top selling cigarette for the 
past eighteen years. He described the inadequacies of current scientific
 knowledge, claiming for example that mouse studies have failed to show 
causality between tobacco and cancer. He also claimed that 
epidemiological research has failed to show environmental tobacco smoke 
to be as a risk factor for cancer. He discussed environmental tobacco 
smoke within the context of an airline attendant lawsuit and commented 
on the Environmental Protection Agency's decision to classify it as a 
carcinogen. The witness addressed the role of the government in 
regulating environmental tobacco smoke. He also discussed youth 
marketing, the role of nicotine in attracting new smokers, and the role 
of the Tobacco Institute.               </description>
  <scanner>Internet Archive HTML5 Uploader 1.4.2</scanner>
  <subject>tobacco; cigarette; deposition; litigation; advertising; industry response; youth; &lt;a href='http://www.archive.org/browse.php?field=subject&amp;mediatype=movies&amp;collection=industry-archives'&gt;Browse by keywords in UCSF industry videos&lt;/a&gt;</subject>
  <title>Deposition of ANDREW J. SCHINDLER, April 14, 1997, ENGLE v. R.J. REYNOLDS TOBACCO CO.</title>
  <publicdate>2013-12-04 21:10:00</publicdate>
  <uploader>rachel.taketa@ucsf.edu</uploader>
  <addeddate>2013-12-04 21:10:00</addeddate>
  <date>1997-04-14</date>
  <year>1997</year>
  <sound>sound</sound>
  <color>color</color>
  <credits>View more information at the &lt;a href="https://www.industrydocuments.ucsf.edu/docs/srhg0189" rel="nofollow"&gt;UCSF Industry Documents Library&lt;/a&gt;</credits>
  <backup_location>ia905800_27</backup_location>
</metadata>
